<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lucy M. Li, PhD</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lucy M. Li, PhD</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking back at my first R scripts</title>
      <link>/2017/08/09/looking-back-at-my-first-r-scripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/08/09/looking-back-at-my-first-r-scripts/</guid>
      <description>I regularly hung out with bacteria on petri dishes during my undergraduate days. Since then, I have become good friends with all things Bayesian, played around with particle filters, and enthusiastically adopted R Markdown as my notetaking method of choice. I still hang out with pathogens, but only on screen and in the form of plushie toys. This is my first blog post, so I&amp;rsquo;ll start from the beginning with my first foray into the world of maths and computing (my first R scripts and my first computational project report).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2016 21:48:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description> Infectious disease scientist using multiple sources of data, statistical methods, and stochastic models to understand how pathogens spread.
Research Interests  Dynamic and stochastic models of infectious diseases Statistical inference/learning - how to infer unobserved quantities and predict future events Sequential Monte Carlo methods Phylodynamics - using genetic data to understand how infectious diseases spread  Positions  Postdoctoral research fellow at Center for Communicable Disease Dynamics, Harvard T.H. Chan School of Public Health (current)  Education  PhD in Infectious Disease Epidemiology @ Imperial College London, UK (2013-2017) Computational Biology MPhil with Distinction @ University of Cambridge, UK (2012-2013) Biology BSc with First Class Honours @ Imperial College London, UK (2009-2012)  Teaching  Time-series Analysis in Infectious Disease Epidemiology, Stat 131, Harvard University Department of Statistics (2017)  Life outside of science  Treasurer of Harvard Chan Postdoctoral Association (2017-2018) President of Imperial College Yoga Club (2014-2015) Treasurer of Imperial College Badminton Club (2011-2012) Piano tutor (2009)  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>